fasebj.org 2019-06-23

# FASEB > About FASEB > Privacy Policy

[Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology](http://www.faseb.org/) (“FASEB”), 9650 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20814.

FASEB is committed to protecting your privacy and providing a safe online experience. This Privacy Policy applies to the FASEB websites and governs data collection and usage. We take this matter very seriously and have instituted policies and procedures to ensure your privacy rights are protected. The following outlines our Privacy Policy and details the measures we have taken to safeguard and protect your privacy.

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page.

## What information does FASEB collect?

The data FASEB collects is used to help us better serve our constituents and to further our mission to advance health and well-being by promoting research and education in biological and biomedical sciences through collaborative advocacy and service to our societies and their members.

The information you provide to us will be used to keep you up-to-date on areas for which you have expressed interest. We will exercize discretion in the use of your personal information, as further described in this policy. It will be used only to support our relationship with you or your organization.

If at any time you no longer wish to receive notifications or promotions from FASEB, we will remove you from our active mailing list immediately.

If you no longer wish to be contacted for:

  * Marketing, advocacy or general communications, please contact [info@faseb.org](mailto:info@faseb.org)
  * Journal subscription communications, please contact [subscriptions@faseb.org](mailto:subscriptions@faseb.org)
  * Conference or Meeting communications, please contact [MeetingsPrivacy@faseb.org](mailto:MeetingsPrivacy@faseb.org)

It is our general policy to collect and store only personal information that our website visitors, clients, customers and constituents knowingly provide.

## Use of Information – How does FASEB use data collected?

FASEB uses information voluntarily submitted by members and other customers in the following ways:

**General Users.   **FASEB does not collect any personal information from users browsing our website. When you visit our website, we may automatically collect statistics about your visit. This information does not identify you personally, but rather about your visit to our website. We may monitor statistics such as how many people visit our site, which pages people visit, from which domains our visitors come and which browsers people use. We use these statistics about your visit for aggregation purposes only. Aggregate data are only used for internal and marketing purposes and do not provide any personally identifying information.

Personal information and information specific to a requested activity may be collected along with a request for service, product, marketing, event or advocacy resources. For example, this information may include your company or organization name, contact name, address, telephone number, email address and services requested.

**FASEB Conference Registrants, Journal Subscriptions, Products, Services and Other Marketing and Advocacy Communications.   **Generally, FASEB uses data collected to improve its own web content; to respond to visitors' interests, needs and preferences; to further FASEB’s mission; and to deliver products and services.

To gain access to some resources and personalization features on FASEB websites, users are asked to register and provide some limited information. This information is submitted voluntarily. FASEB asks users to provide information related to supporting the specific service being provided. Similar information may be requested by FASEB through conference or seminar registration, abstract submissions, publication orders, subscriptions, and contest/award applications.

Additionally, for some emails sent by FASEB to users through its listservs and electronic newsletters, we will collect specific information regarding what the recipient does with that email. For those emails, FASEB will monitor whether a recipient subsequently clicks through to links provided in the message. Other information collected through this tracking feature includes: email address of a user, the date and time of the user's "click," a message number, name of the list from which the message was sent, tracking URL number and destination page. FASEB only uses this information to enhance its products and distribution of those products to its constituents.

**Credit Card Account Information.   **FASEB does not disclose credit card account information provided by its customers. When customers choose to pay using their credit cards, FASEB submits the information needed to obtain payment via a secure internet protocol to the appropriate payment gateway.

## How does FASEB use cookies?

Cookies are files that contain information created by a web server that can be stored on a user's hard disk for use either during a particular session ("per-session" cookie) or for future use ("persistent" cookie). FASEB uses cookies only to facilitate automated activity, store and track passwords, determine appropriate solicitations, and review navigation patterns. Cookies are not used to disseminate significant information about users over the Internet or to analyze any information that users have knowingly or unknowingly provided. When a user registers, the system will ask whether the user approves of the attachment of a cookie. Users may instruct their Internet browsers to opt out of accepting a "persistent" cookie and rather accept only a "per-session" cookie, but will need to login each time they visit the site to enjoy the full benefits. If the user declines the attachment of any cookie, the user may not have access to the full benefits of the website. Additional information on FASEB’s use of cookies is described in our Cookies Policy.

## Other websites & links

This website may contain links to other websites. This Privacy Policy does not cover the privacy practices of websites external to FASEB and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites, partners, or affiliates. You should review any privacy policies of such websites.

## Security

FASEB uses reasonable administrative, logical, physical and managerial measures to safeguard personal information. No measures can be guaranteed to provide 100% security, however, and accordingly FASEB cannot guarantee the security of your information against loss, theft, or unauthorized access and use.

## What means of redress are available?

If you suspect FASEB has handled its personal information in a manner that does not comply with this privacy policy, please contact us by emailing to [privacy@faseb.org](mailto:privacy@faseb.org) or by writing to us at:

FASEB  
ATTN: Data Security Officer  
Information Technology Department  
9650 Rockville Pike  
Bethesda, MD 20814

## For Residents of the European Union

FASEB is the abbreviated name of the [Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology](http://www.faseb.org/), located at 9650 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, Maryland 20814.

FASEB recognizes principles and requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) adopted by the European Union. For more information on GDPR, please visit the [European Commissions’ GDPR Website](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en). In addition to the universal privacy policies stated earlier in this document, FASEB will, so far as is reasonably practical, comply with the specific Data Protection Principles contained in the Data Protection Act to ensure all data is:

  * Fairly and lawfully processed
  * Obtained and used for specific and clearly stated purposes
  * Adequate, relevant, and not excessive
  * Accurate and up-to-date
  * Not kept for longer than necessary
  * Processed in accordance with your rights
  * Secure

### What is personal information?

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors, clients, customers and constituents. This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to personal data.

The GDPR aims to protect the “personal data” or personal information of individuals within the EU and covers many processing activities, including collection, storage, consultation, transfer, and destruction, of this data. “Personal data” means information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. You can be identified from information such as your name, email address, phone number, home address, driver’s license number, and passport number. You may also be identifiable from information such as an online identifier, IP address, unique device ID or cookie.

### What information do we collect about you?

We collect information about you when visiting FASEB websites relating to your use of FASEB sites, collected using cookies. We also collect information when you request our services and when voluntarily completing surveys, contact forms, responding to marketing and advocacy communications and participating in FASEB events and activities. We only hold this information as long as it is necessary to fulfill a contract, provide you with requested services, including FASEB newsletters and communication updates, or where we believe you will be interested in FASEB activities.

### How will we use the information about you?

We collect information about you to process your order, manage your account and, if you agree, to email you about other products and services we think may be of interest to you.

We use your information collected from the website to personalize your repeat visits to our websites.

We may share your information if you indicate you would like to learn more about a FASEB society or partner during a meeting registration process or in your communication preferences.

### Legitimate interests & performance of a contract

There are a number of lawful reasons we can use (or ‘process’) your personal information, including ‘legitimate interests’ and ‘performance of a contract.’

Broadly speaking, Legitimate Interests means we can process your personal information if:

  * We have a genuine and legitimate reason to do so; and
  * That genuine and legitimate reason is not outweighed by any undue harm to of your rights and interests.

Performance of a Contract means we can use (or ‘process’) your personal information if:

  * Data processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with or on behalf of the data subject.

For data which does not meet either the Legitimate Interest or Performance of a Contract criteria, we will obtain your consent prior to collecting your personal data.

### Marketing & advocacy

We would like to send you information about our services and news. If you have consented to receive marketing or advocacy information, you may opt out at a later date.

You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for these purposes or giving your information to third party partners or suppliers by modifying your communication preferences or contacting us at the email addresses listed below.

If you no longer wish to be contacted for:

  * Marketing or advocacy communications, please contact [info@faseb.org](mailto:info@faseb.org)
  * Journal subscription communications, please contact [subscriptions@faseb.org](mailto:subscriptions@faseb.org)
  * Conference or Meeting communications, please contact [MeetingsPrivacy@faseb.org](mailto:MeetingsPrivacy@faseb.org)

We gather statistics pertaining to email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletters and other communication resources.

### Conference & events

Generally, those who wish to attend FASEB conferences events will register for those events online, by email or over the telephone. During the process of that registration, you share with us personal information about yourself which generally includes contact information, demographics pertaining to your profession and payment information. Alternatively, we may collect association membership data directly from the organization to which you belong.

### How FASEB uses your event registration data

Personal Information Registration information will be part of a database that is accessible only to FASEB employees and conference organizers.

FASEB Scientific Research Conferences (SRCs) use your contact information to provide you with up to-date information about current conferences as well as future SRCs.

  * A participant list is available online to registered conference participants that includes your name, institution, institution address, and email.
  * Your name, email address, lodging type (and roommate, if applicable), and conference you registered to attend are shared with hotels if you requested lodging accommodations.
  * A survey company receives your name, email address, and conference you registered to attend in order for participants to receive an online evaluation form.
  * For those participants that are reimbursed for their participation at the conference, contact information is sent to our internal FASEB accounting database, and any bank or wire transfer institution that accounting uses in order to facilitate the payment.
  * If participants request information from a FASEB member or non-member society, or another FASEB department, via the FASEB SRC department, contact information will be shared to facilitate the request. FASEB SRC does not sell your contact information to third parties.

### Retaining & deleting personal data

Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes is not kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

In general, we will retain your personal data while we are actively engaging in an activity with you and for a maximum period of no longer than seven years following the completion of that activity.

Notwithstanding the other provisions, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

### Your rights

GDPR, as implemented on 25 May 2018, gives all individual resudents of the EU a number of rights relating to their personal data held by companies, organizations and other third parties. These are:

  * **Informed:   ** We will tell you exactly how we use your data in clear, plain language.
  * **Legal Bases:   **We will store or use your data only to support the performance of a contract, to further a legitimate interest, to comply with a legal obligation or with your consent.
  * **Access and Portability:   **Obtain an export of all data FASEB has collected and processed for you in a machine-readable format(e.g. .csv or Excel file formats)
  * **Modification:   **Request changes or updates to any personal data FASEB stores.
  * **Erasure:   **Request that FASEB purge all personal identifying information.

### How to contact us

If you would like to exercise a right you have under GDPR, please contact us at the email or mailing address below.

Please contact [privacy@faseb.org](mailto:privacy@faseb.org) or write to us at:

FASEB  
ATTN: Data Security Officer  
Information Technology Department  
9650 Rockville Pike  
Bethesda, MD 20814
